

Alexander Jansing

Data / Software Engineer

28 April 1989



Liverpool, NY 13088

apjansing.github.io



(315) 601-8991



alexander.jansing@gmail.com

About me —

Air Force and Air National Guard veteran with a Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics and a planned graudation date of May 2019 to finish a Master of Science in Computer Science. Attends local Meetups and hackathons to further knowledge and get a better feel for professional environments outside of the defense industry.

Skills

Java, Python

Scala, MATLAB

HTML, CSS, Javascript

Bash

Databases

Hadoop, Accumulo

MongoDB, Postgres

OrientDB, TitanDB, Spark GraphX

Bash*3.7 HTML*4 Java*5.8

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

interests

Free time is spent with friends, at hackathons, writing code, or unwinding with a good game or book.

education

Relevant courses:

2015-2019 M.S. Computer and Information Sciences Focus in Software Engineering and Mathematics

Quantum Computing Formal Methods

AI Topic: Data Science Big Data Platforms Numerical Diff Equations Machine Learning Parallel Computing

2012-2015 B.S. Applied Mathematics Cognate in Computer Science

SUNY Oswego

SUNY Polytechnic

experience

2018—Present Software Engineer, Mid – Computer Science

Working as an Implementation Specialist on the Swift project. Using Concourse, Sonarqube, Docker, and Bash scripts to create CI/CD pipelines that can be applied to arbitrary projects with minimal adaptation.

2018–2018 Software Engineer, Asc

Lockheed Martir

Worked on a variety of projects involving signal processing. Developed analytics for Noise Reduction and identification of Modulation techniques using methods like KMeans and DenseNet.

2016–2018 Data Scientist, Junior – Computer Science

Booz Allen Hamilton

Worked on the AFRL Active Insights project that was demoed at GeoINT2017 and will be demoed at GeoINT2018. Work focused on ETL, designing a data lake, and provenance tracking.

2015-2016 Graduate Assistant

SUNY Polytechnic

Graded homework, held office hours, and designed grading schemes for Finite Mathematics.

awards

2018 Open House Planner

Hack Upstate XII

Grand Prize and Best Use of Esri Technology

A project that was inspired by a real-world problem.

"What if two houses are significantly far apart, open at similar times, and there are other houses in each of their respective neighborhoods that open at different times? Is there a way I can plan my day of house hunting so that I can attend all of the open houses?"

.

2018 Move Helper

Hack Mohawk Valley

Best Use or Open Data

2018 Buffalo Crime Data

Hack Upstate XI

Buffalo Civic Innovation Challenge



Alexander Jansing

Data / Software Engineer

28 April 1989



Liverpool, NY 13088



(315) 601-8991



apjansing.github.io



alexander.jansing@gmail.com

About me –

Air Force and Air National Guard veteran with a Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics and a planned graudation date of May 2019 to finish a Master of Science in Computer Science. Attends local Meetups and hackathons to further knowledge and get a better feel for professional environments outside of the defense industry.

Skills

Java, Python

Scala, MATLAB

HTML, CSS, Javascript

Bash

Databases

Hadoop, Accumulo

MongoDB, Postgres

OrientDB, TitanDB, Spark GraphX

Bash*3.7 HTML*4 Java*5.8

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Presentations

2016

An Overview and Brief Tutorial of Niagara Files Booz Allen Hamilton Tech Talks Booz Allen Hamilton's internal webcast and conference line. Niagara Files (Nifi) is a digraph ETL program that provides a web-based UI, loss tolerance, data provenance, and the ability to create custom processors using a Maven archetype. Covered what a FlowFile is and some of the most important concepts of Nifi that are needed to understand before working with Nifi.

2015 Lie Algebras

SUNY Oswego Mathematics Department

Lie algebras have two special operators, the Lie bracket and the inner product and they both have special characteristics that impose algebraic and geometry restrictions on the spaces they apply to. We looked at how they interact, and wrote programs in Sage (Python) that generate general forms of the matrix representations of these interactions.

Computer skills

Languages Java, Python, Scala, Matlab, R, Groovy, Bash, Languages, Javascript, Bash, HTML,

CSS

Databases Accumulo, OrientDB, TitanDB, MongoDB, Postgres, Hadoop

Technologies Git, Jira, Confluence, Nifi, Apex, Spark, AWS, Maven, Docker, Docker Com-

pose, Concourse

Systems Linux (CentOS and Ubuntu), Mac, Windows